Guide to the Residential Child Care Project records, 1981-1997.
Residential Child Care Project records, 1981-1997.
- New York State Child Protective Services Training Institute, Trainer's Manual, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Trainer's Manual, Week 1 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Trainer's Manual Week 2 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Guidebook, Week 1 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Social Services Training Program, State University College at Buffalo, Richard McCowan, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Correspondence with New York State Federation on Child Abuse and Neglect, James S. Cameron, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Correspondence with State Department of Social Services, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Research in Review, Perspectives for Social Services Utilization, Child Protective Services Training Institute Funded, Issue Number 8, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Lesson Plan, Module I - Day 1, Pre-investigation and Investigation (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, Michael A. Nunno, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- New York State Child Protection Training Institute, Cover Letter to County Commissioners Outlining Program, Draft of Module I, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Evaluation proposal for CPS Training Institute, Section 7, prepared by Michael Nunno (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Training Project, Michael Nunno (handwritten notes) (Box 7, Folder 13)
- The Child Protective Service Instructional Development Project, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Educational Materials, A Curriculum on Child Abuse and Neglect, Institute of Child Behavior and Development University of Iowa, Regional Child Abuse and Neglect Resource Center (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Psychodynamics of Child Abuse, Neglect and Battering Syllabus, Sara Pines, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Internal Communication Form, Department of Social Services and Housing, Help Yourself - A CPS Resource Utilization Plan for DSSH Social Workers, by G. Senner, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Family Day Care/Foster Care/Homemaker Service/Training Needs Assessment For CPS, prepared by Family Life Development Center and Social Change Advocates (Box 7, Folder 13)
- A Self Instruction Booklet for Assessment of Child Abuse Potential by C. Daughtry, J. Tapp, D. Wegenast, M. Wijnberg, State University College at Buffalo, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Goal Oriented Social Work Services: A Workbook (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Goal Planning in Social Work: Trainer Manual (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Parent/Professional Training Package (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Lay Therapy Training Program, Program Overview Pamphlet, sponsored by the Schenectady Junior League, N. Trimpoli, S. Spaulding (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Parent Study/Discussion Group, Leader Manual, Pilot Materials by Kent Hamdorf, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Unpolished Curriculum Work Papers, Laboratory of Psychology, National Institute of Mental Health, May Aaronson and Earl S. Schaefer, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Child Abuse Workshop II, George Warren Brown School of Social Work Washington University, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Correspondence concerning the use of restraints in Juvenile Facilities with Youth Law Center, Department of the Youth Authority, California, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Correspondence with America Association for Protecting Children, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Emotional Maltreatment of Children by James Cameron and Michael Nunno, Fourth National Conference on Child Abuse and Neglect, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- New York State Child Protective Services Training Institute, 1983-1984 Program, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- New York State Child Protective Services Training Institute, 1984-1985 Program, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- New York State Child Protective Services Training Institute, 1986-1987 Program, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- New York State Child Protective Services Training Institute, 1988-1989 Program, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- New York State Child Protective Services Training Institute, 1989-1990 Program, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- New York State Child Protective Services Training Institute, 1994-1995 Program Announcement, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Residential Child Care Program, 1994-1995 Announcement, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Accountability, Protecting Children, Volume 2, Number 4, Winter, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Child Protection Polices in Europe, International Federation of Educative Communities (FICE), 1990 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Correspondence with Indiana University concerning a Survey of State's Contractual Training Arrangements, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- New York Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Children, One Hundred Twelfth Annual Report of the President, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Correspondence with The Institute for the Prevention of Child Abuse, Ontario, Canada, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Institutional Abuse of Children Conference, National Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Children, Leicester, LE, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Correspondence with New York State, Department of Social Services, Special Services for Children, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- A Proposal to Implement the Child Protective Services Training Academy, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Residential Child Maltreatment: An Unrecognized Problem in the United States by George Thomas (Box 7, Folder 17)
- The Child Care Worker's Guide to Understanding State Policy on Discipline of Children in Foster Care prepared by Peter Kasius, Training and Technical Assistance, Office of Family and Children's Services, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Correspondence with Greg Smiles, Institutional Abuse Project, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Correspondence with Ellen Ehrenreich concerning Preliminary Contacts for Institutional Abuse Component, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- A Conference on Models for Prevention of Institutional Child Abuse: What Can We Do Inside and Out?, North Brunswick, NJ, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Correspondence with Connecticut Department of Children and Youth Services, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Excellence in Training Conference, Therapeutic Crisis Intervention for Residential Child Care Staff by Martha Holden and Raymond Taylor, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- The Investigation of Child Abuse and Neglect in Out of Home Care, Investigating the Maltreatment of Children Training, Baton Rouge, LA, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- I CA/N: Make A Difference, Prevention Forum Series for Residential Child Care Facilities in New York State, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- National Residential Child Care Training Project, Family Life Development Center, Cornell University, Faculty and Staff (Box 8, Folder 1)
- I CA/N: Make A Difference, Preventing Institutional Child Abuse and Neglect in Residential Care, A Symposium, December, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Specialized Training in the Investigation of Out-of-Home Child Abuse and Neglect, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Specialized Training in the Investigation of Out-of-Home Child Abuse and Neglect, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Guidebook for Louisiana Child Protective Service Staff, Specialized Training in the Investigation of Out of-Home Child Abuse and Neglect Cases, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Correspondence on Crisis Control Project Development, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Institutional Self-Assessment Project Methodology: Goal Assessment and Remediation Process prepared by Family Life Development Center, Cornell University, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Institutional Self-Assessment Project: GARP (Goal Assessment and Remediation Process), 1983 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Institutional Assessment Project, Monthly Narrative, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Proposed Demonstration Project in Institutional Abuse Prevention in New York State (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Green Chimneys, GARP (Goal Assessment and Remediation Process), 1983 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Catholic Charities of Onondaga County: Residential Services, GARP (Goal Assessment and Remediation Process) Project, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- National Residential Child Care Training Project Narrative, Year Two, Section I-V, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Crisis Control and Institutional Assessment: Alternatives for the Prevention of CA/N In Residential Settings by Michael Nunno, Michael Budlong, & Josephine Pasciullo (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Residential Child Care Project, Final Report, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Residential Child Care Project, Quarterly Report, Fourth Quarter Overview, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Residential Child Care Project, Quarterly Report, First Quarter of Second Year Overview, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Residential Child Care Project, Quarterly Report, Third Quarter of Second Year Overview, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- New York State Institutional Assessment, Monthly Reports (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Drawer Four: Case Materials, SCR, UCR (Box 8, Folder 3)
- What Kids Can Tell Us: A Critical Assessment of Interview Strategies, Training Curriculum for Trainers, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- What Kids Can Tell Us, Follow-up evaluation, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- What Kids Can Tell Us, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- What Kids Can Tell Us, Research Proposal and Correspondence, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Take Aways, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Child Abuse and Child Development, Part Four, Communicating with Children, Sharon Hall, Kingston University, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Faculty Presentation Materials: Interview Protocols, The Step-Wise Interview, John Yuille, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Faculty Presentation Materials: What Kids Can Tell Us, Linda McBride, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Faculty Presentation Materials: Michael Toglia, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Faculty Presentation Materials: Self Assessment Form, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Faculty Presentation Materials: Survey of Beliefs About Memory, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Faculty Presentation Materials: Interview Elements, Helen Hembrooke, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- What Kids Can Tell Us: Take Away Notes, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Critical Thinking for Social Workers: Vignettes for Game A, Game B (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Memorandum of Good Practice: On video recorded interviews with child witnesses for criminal proceedings, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Virginia Child Protection Newsletter, Fall 1994 (43), 1994 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Computer Assisted Interviews of Children Who May Have Been Abused by Faller, DeVoe, Mildred, Wilson, and Ferraro (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Letter from Jean Montoya, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Legal and Therapeutic Interventions with Incestuous Families by Jeffrey Haugaard and Corine Samwel (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Child Sex Rings: A Behavioral Analysis, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Correspondence with Alaska Division of Family and Youth Services, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Part 1: An Inductive Approach to Children's Cognitive/Social Development by Deb Poole (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Language Development: Implications for Interviewing Children by Amye Warren (Box 8, Folder 6)
- What Kids Can Tell Us: Participant Survey and Evaluation Results, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Registers: Federal and Central, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- New York State Central Register for Child Abuse and Neglect: An Exploration of Research Potential by Maxine Schoggen, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Governor's Conference on Families, Region V, Cornell University, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Concept Paper for A World Conference on Child Abuse, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- The Third World Within and Abroad: A Concept Paper on A Project of The World Conference on Maltreatment and Children's Rights by Llyod Street, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Governor's Conference on Families, Delegates Meeting, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Attorneys Conference on Child Abuse and Neglect, Elmira, NY, September-October, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Legal Aid Society, Juvenile Rights Division, Child Protective Proceedings (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Child Abuse and Neglect: A Handbook for proceedings in the New York Family Court of the State of New York by Michael Cohen & David Lanser (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Keynote Address by New York City Council President Carol Bellamy, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- New York State Governor's Conference on Families, In Retrospect, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Four Unresolved Issues Family Court Judges Face in Child Abuse and Neglect Cases by Jose Alfaro, May, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Correspondence on White House Conference, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Legal and Psychological Issues in the Testimony of Children by John Doris (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Confidential Cases of Sexual Abuse: For Professional Use (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Statement Validity Analysis, Content Criteria for Statement Analysis by John Yuille (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Protecting Children, American Humane Association, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Crisis Control and Institutional Assessment: Alternatives for Prevention of Child Abuse and Neglect in Residential Settings, Proposal, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Barnardos Prospectus, Spring Hill School, Care and Education, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Children in Scotland & Central Region Conference, Stirling, Understanding & Managing Difficult Behavior, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Dealing With Challenging Behavior, Care and Control of Young People in Residential Settings, 1 Day Conference, London, UK (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Quality of Foster Care, Correspondence with Jeff Haugaard and John Eckenrode (Box 9, Folder 4)
- New York State Child Protective Services Training Institute, Concept Paper & Original Proposal by John Doris, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- New York State Child Protective Services Training Institute, Application for Training Contract, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- New York State Child Protective Services Training Institute, Residential Child Care Project, Working With the Adolescent In Residential Care, Trainer's Manual by Martha Holden, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Newsletter-"Refocus", 1996 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Children and Residential Experiences: Creating Conditions for Change reference guide, 2007 (Box 9, Folder 8)